# **Sean Haines**

E-Mail: seanhaines13@gmail.com • Github: https://github.com/sseeaann

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/sseeaann • Portfolio: http://sseeaann.github.io

## **SUMMARY**

My career has solidified my motivation for the end user while; working in small non-profits has built a repertoire of doing whatever it takes to get the job done. As a web developer, I am proficient in LAMP, MEAN and Ruby on Rails with the ability to develop web applications from concept to implementation. Experienced with user research, testing and development. I have a great deal of passion for Front End development, client involvement/focus and working with an open and driven team.

# **TECHNICAL TOOLBOX**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SQL, PHP, JavaScript

**Preprocessors:** Sass, Jade

**Libraries and Frameworks:** Angular JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, CodeIgniter, Express.js, Socket.io,

Ruby on Rails, AJAX

**Databases:** NoSQL (Mongodb), Mongoose.js, SQL (MySQL, SQLite)

**Servers:** Apache, Node.js

**Dev Tools:** Sublime Text, Git/Github, Terminal

Methodology: MVC, OOP, RESTful

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Full Stack Web Development Boot camp, 2015

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, Washington

## **Bachelor of Arts in Community Health Education**, 2008

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

- BREWbeacon (Ruby on Rails): Web application where users can locate where their favorite beers are sold or served, login/register accounts, find/post homebrew recipes. TECH: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Google Maps Api, Gems: Bcrypt (user authentication), Simple\_form, Bootstrapsass, RESTful.
- **Node.js Cars (MEAN):** Using the basic CRUD operations, users can add cars to the database, view each car's profile page, edit and delete cars. *TECH: Angular.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose.js/Mongodb, Bootstrap.*
- Chat Room (MEAN): Web app for real-time chat room with chat history storage. TECH: Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, Mongoose.js/Mongodb.
- Ninja Gold Game (PHP): CodeIgniter web app game where a player can hunt for gold and gamble in a casino where the casino has a 70% chance of winning. TECH: PHP, CodeIgniter, Bootstrap.

# **Sean Haines**

E-Mail: <a href="mailto:seanhaines13@gmail.com">seanhaines13@gmail.com</a> • Github: <a href="https://github.com/sseeaann">https://github.com/sseeaann</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://sseeaann.github.io">https://sseeaann.github.io</a> • Portfolio: <a href="https://sseeaann.github.io">https://sseeaann.github.io</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Web Developer,** May 2015 – *Present* Freelance

• Web design and development.

**Team Lead, Mar.** 2013 – Feb. 2015

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

- Assisted with data base development through hands on user experience and research. Was
  part of the super user implementation group assisting with program rollout. Continuously
  monitored and communicated database user experiences and troubleshooting with IT
  support and data base vendor.
- Met with case management teams to discuss daily tasks and monthly goals. Closely supported the Program Director by maintaining daily planning and operations to ensure high levels of efficiency and customer service within the organization.
- Assisted with the screening, hiring and training of new staff while managing the day-to-day operations of the case management team.
- Coordinated new strategies and process improvements. Communicated and execute process changes to internal and external care teams. Compiled monthly, quarterly and annual reports showing the success and growth of all programs.

#### Case Manager II, May 2010 – Feb. 2013

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

- Restructured dental program's case management process to increase efficiency. Increased client referral numbers by 1,200% over 2 years.
- Scheduled high volumes of medical and dental appointments across multiple counties for uninsured and Medicaid clients. Daily data entry of incoming referrals, medical chart notes, enrollment applications, and clinical records requests.
- Communicated with clients, vendors, clinical staff, and program partners through email, phones, written mail, and in person. Developed numerous case management training materials. Conducted program evaluations. Experienced with Lean methodology.

#### Eligibility and Enrollment Specialist, Jun. 2008 – Apr. 2010

Coalition of Community Health Clinics, Portland, Oregon

• Processed all patient applications, enrollments and denials. I was responsible for the coordination of patient to provider assignments, patient orientations, surveys, appointments, and interpretive services. Assisted patients access health resources via phone and email correspondence, while complying with HIPAA guidelines to ensure the security of patient confidentiality. Supported programs through data management and reporting, quality assurance, website editing and improvements.